Today we have gathered here on the right occasion
今天我們聚集在一個合適的場合
and very auspicious day to worship Shri Ganesha.
和非常吉祥的日子去敬拜錫呂‧格涅沙。
Shri Ganesha is the first Deity that was created
格涅沙是第一位被創造的神祇，
so that the whole Universe is filled with auspiciousness,
所以整個宇宙都充滿吉祥，
with peace, bliss, and spirituality.
平和，福氣和靈性。
He is the source.
祂是源頭
He’s the source of spirituality.
祂是靈性的源頭
As a result of that all other things follow.
因此，其他事物跟隨。
Like when it rains and is windy
就像當下雨和刮風，
you feel a coolness in the atmosphere.
你會感到空氣中的清涼。
In the same way when Shri Ganesha emits His Power
同樣，當錫呂‧格涅沙散發祂的力量，
we feel all these three things within and without.
我們內在和外在都感到這三種東西。
But it has been so unfortunate, specially in the West,
但很不幸，特別在西方，
that the most important fundamental Deity
這位最重要基本的神祇
has been completely not only neglected,
不單被忽視，
but insulted and crucified.
還徹底地被侮辱和被迫害。
So today though I did not want to say anything
今天雖然我不想說任何
to upset you people, but I must tell you
令你們感到不安的說話，但我必須告訴你，
that worshiping Shri Ganesha means there has to be
敬拜錫呂‧格涅沙代表你內在
a thorough cleansing within you.
必須完全潔淨
When you worship Shri Ganesha
當你敬拜錫呂‧格涅沙，
keep your mind clean, keep your heart clean,
請保持你的思維清潔，你的心清潔，
keep your being clean -
你的存有清潔
no thoughts of lust and greed should come up.
也必須沒有任何淫慾和貪婪的思維。
Actually when the Kundalini rises
實際上，當靈量昇起
Ganesha had to be awakened within us,
格涅沙必定在你內裏得到喚醒
the innocence has to come up –
純真也必然出現
which obliterates all such degrading ideas within us.
洗刷你內在所有低下的念頭
If ascent has to be achieved, we have to understand
若要達至昇進，我們必須明白
that we have to mature.
我們必須要成熟
People are sick now.
現在人們病了
All over the western life one feels they are sick.
整個西式生活，他們感到他們病了
Sick because they have never recognized Shri Ganesha.
患病是因為他們不承認錫呂‧格涅沙。
If one Freud came that doesn’t mean that you should accept him.
若佛洛依德到來，並不代表你要接受他
But you did - as if it was such an important thing to be done;
但你卻接受了他，好像這是必須要做的最重要事情
there was nothing more important than that.
沒有比這更重要的。
So today we are faced with our power of ascent
今天，我們要面對我們昇進的力量
and the power of conditionings we have had.
以及我們制約的力量
When Freud talks of conditioning he didn’t know
當佛洛依德談論制約
he was putting another type of horrid conditionings on you,
他不知道他正在把另一種可怕的制約加在你身上，
terrible.
真是可怕。
Sex is not important for human beings at all,
性對人類是完全不重要，
is not at all important.
絕對不重要。
It is only when you want to have children
只在你想有孩子時它才重要
actually a human being
實際上，人類
who is of the highest level will indulge into a sex.
處於最高層次的人類，卻沉迷在性
The lure, the romance, this nonsense and all that
誘惑、羅曼蒂克，這些全都是謬誤
doesn’t exist in a pure mind; it’s all a human creation.
並不存在於純潔的頭腦內，這全是人類創造出來。
And this servility one has to that is so much surprising,
人們屈從於這些事情是很令人驚訝的
it comes from a very low grading within us.
這些都是來自你內在低下的品質，
It comes from the low-graded human beings
來自低下的人類
that one becomes servile to it.
令人屈從於它
You should be the master of that.
你必須是這些的主人
And today when I see around Myself, in the West,
今天，當我看看四周，在西方
which is also part and parcel of the same creation,
那是同一創造的一部分
so much of sickness that has come, I am really aghast,
卻染上那麽多病，我真的嚇呆了
how to turn your attention now to the maturity of sex.
該怎樣把你們的注意力轉向對性有成熟態度
When the sex matures you become a father, a mother,
當性成熟，你成為父親，成為母親
and a pure personality.
以及擁有純潔的人格
When you hear about a ninety-year old woman
當你聽到一位九十歲的女人
marrying a nineteen-year old boy,
與一位十九歲的男孩結婚
I mean, you just don’t understand,
我的意思，是你不會明白
this is - what sort of a society it has been created in this world,
這個世界創造了怎樣的社會
this kind of a stupid behaviour?
怎會有這種愚蠢的行為？
We have to mature ourselves.
我們必須成熟
That doesn’t mean I’m saying austerity at young age,
我不是說在年青時行苦行
that doesn’t mean that. Another absurdity is that.
不是這樣，這是另一種荒謬的行為
But of course you must mature;
當然，你必須成熟
you need a tapasya for that.
為此你需要行苦行
Unimportant thing when become important
當不重要的事情變得重要
and such unimportant thing that they’re just like anything
這種不重要的事情就像
that we have, like we have hair.
我們所擁有的事物，像我們的頭髮
Even if you lose hair it means something.
就算你失去了頭髪，這代表某些意義
But if you lose sex, what’s wrong with it? It’s very good.
但若你失去了性，有甚麽不妥呢？這很好
Good riddance of bad rubbish.
擺脫了壞的垃圾
Such a waste of energy.
這樣浪費精力
So much interest, so much of a precious attention,
那麽多樂趣，那麽多寶貴注意力
so much of auspiciousness is spent
那麽多吉祥都花費在
in this kind of a nonsensical thing.
這種荒謬的事上。
So to worship Ganesha one has to understand
所以敬拜格涅沙，我們要明白
we have to mature.
我們必須成熟
Maturity has to come within us.
我們內在必須成熟
We have to go deeper within ourselves;
我們必須更深入自己
our attention has to go deeper within ourselves, spontaneously.
我們的注意力必須更深入自己，自然地
How do we achieve the depth if we are still like worms?
若我們仍像寄生蟲，我們怎能到達這深度？
Otherwise it’s a great sort of a sacrifice
這是一種偉大的犧牲，
or a pressure on people.
或是對人的壓力。
These tags and these pressures have been very costly
這種標籤和壓力對你們都是非常昂貴
for you people, very costly.
非常昂貴
You have paid through so much;
你們已經付出很多
you have gone through so much. For what?
已經經歷很多，為何要這樣？
So the priorities have to change
所以，先後次序必須改變
if Shri Ganesha is to be worshipped.
若要敬拜錫呂‧格涅沙
What are we worshipping today is the innocence within us.
我們今天敬拜的是我們內在的純真
We are worshipping that is auspicious, which is innocent.
我們敬拜的對象是吉祥的，是純真的
Innocence, which is deep down within us - that’s our character,
純真，是深入我們內在，那就是我們的個性
that’s our nature, that’s what we are born with –
我們的本質，那是與生俱來的
is the basic of this whole Creation;
是整個創造的基礎，
is the essence of this Creation.
是這個創造的精粹
So when matter becomes active, all right, reproduction starts,
當物質變得活躍，繁殖開始
animal stage comes in, then comes the stage of human beings
動物的狀態來臨，跟著來到人類
who are primitive, then comes the stage
最原始的狀態，
where human beings are developed.
跟著是人類已經發展的狀態
Not the way what we understand of the developed world, horrible.
並不是我們所理解的已發展的世界，那是可怕的
I’ll never call them developed by any chance at all.
我永遠也不會稱呼他們為發展
What is development is not outside.
發展並不是外在的
What is the within development one has to see.
我們要看到的是內在的發展
What have we grown inside?
我們內在生長了甚麽？
What have we got inside ourselves?
我們內在得到了甚麽？
Anything that gross, big, is plastic, of that kind.
任何粗糙的，巨大的，是塑料，就是這類東西
The one which hasn’t got any inner power grown,
內在的力量並沒有生長
say, for example, I give you a mango.
就如我給你一個芒果，
I said, “All right, now you eat it.”
我說︰「好吧，你現在吃吧
And you see it just has the cover and nothing inside it,
你只看到它的外皮，內在卻甚麽也沒有
what will you eat? Will you eat that plastic?
你吃的是甚麽？你會否吃這塑料？
Anything that grown like that is plastic, is dead.
任何生長成這樣的東西都是塑料，是死的。
What is the substance inside, let’s see.
內在的物質是甚麽，讓我們看看
What is our substance within ourselves?
我們內在是甚麽物質？
This is what Christ preached – morality point.
這是基督所宣揚的--道德。
So important for Him it was.
對基督這是很重要的
Because after dharma, which was a balance,
因為正法之後，是平衡
where of course morality is very important,
當然道德亦非常重要
but it was necessary for Christ to talk of the innate,
但基督需要談及天生的
deeper morality, which is a part and parcel of a being,
深度的道德，那是存有的一部分
it is not just taught, or told, or frightened
不是被教導而來，被告訴而來或是因為懼怕神
because there’s a fear of God and wrath of God.
懼怕神的怒氣而被恐嚇而來
But it should be your own innate light,
但必須是你內在天生而來的光
that’s why Christ talked about it.
所以基督談及它
And the same Christ was used to demolish innocence.
同一位基督卻被用作破壞純真。
And I would not say that people were not warned.
我不可以說人們沒有被警告
Freud was not the only person who was born.
佛洛依德並不是唯一出生的人
The other day I went to Prado in Spain
某天我到西班牙的Prado
and I saw paintings after paintings of the hell.
看到一幅又一幅繪畫地獄的油畫，
And all these modern times we see those lanky pankies
在這個現代，我們看到裸體
going around without clothes, sort of people were shown
瘦長的人四處走動，這類人展示
with all kind of funny things, stupid things they were doing.
他們在做著各式各樣荒謬愚蠢的事情
This was Bosch. I was surprised, a German, Bosch,
這是Bosch。我感到很驚訝，這位Bosch的德國人
who showed all this nonsense there, very clearly - way to hell,
在這裏展示這些荒謬的東西，非常清楚，走往地獄的途徑，
then the attack of the death, all these things.
以及死亡的攻擊，所有這類的東西
I mean he was quite a recent person.
我的意思是他是一位近代人。
If you call Blake as a madcap, so what about Bosch?
若你稱呼威廉布來克為魯莽的人，那麽Bosch又怎樣？
Everybody’s a madcap, except for the stupid useless people.
每一個人都很魯莽，除了那些愚蠢無用的人。
So much warning has come for us. For example, we can say,
很多警告已經出現。例如，我們可以說
since long we know about hell.
我們早已知道地獄。
Mahavira of all the persons wrote so clearly about hell.
摩訶維瓦(Mahavira)以及所有的人都清楚的寫下有關地獄
This is hell.
這是地獄。
But in the West the priorities are absolutely upside down.
在西方，先後次序卻完全相反
What is your power? Just think of it. Think within yourself.
甚麽是你的力量？只想想，想想你的內在
Is it mental power that’s important?
思維的力量是否重要？
I have told you mental power has nothing to do,
我曾經告訴你思維的力量毫不重要
because it is just linear, it moves in one direction, falls off,
因為它是直線的，它只向一個方向移動，降低
comes back to you. It has no substance in it.
再回來，它並無任何實體
It’s just a mind projection, plastic.
它只是思維的投射，塑膠的。
What is your emotional power?
你的情緒力量又怎麽樣？
Emotions that you have takes you where?
情緒會把你帶到那裏？
See you have emotions for, even good emotions you have.
你看你有情緒，你甚至有好的情緒。
Say, you love your wife very much.
例如，你很愛你的妻子
Where does it take you?
這可以把你帶到怎樣的境地？
There was a poet called Tulsidasa who loved his wife very much
有一位名為Tulsidasa的詩人，他很愛他的妻子，
and she had gone to her mother’s place.
她去了她母親的地方
So he couldn’t bear it and went to see her
他忍不住去找她
and he climbed over to her balcony and she got a fright.
他爬上她的露台，把她嚇了一跳。
She said, “How did you climb?”
她說︰「你怎樣爬上來？」
He said, “You had put a rope there.” She said, “No.”
他說︰「你放了一條繩子在這裏。」她說︰「我沒有。」
And they saw it was a big snake hanging.
他們看到一條大蛇在掛著。
So she said, “The amount of love you have for me,
所以她說︰「若你對神的愛有你對我的愛那麽多，
if you have that for God, where will you be?”
你可以處於怎樣的境地？
So where does these emotions take you - to frustration,
這個情緒可以把你帶來甚麽，帶來挫敗
to unhappiness, to our destruction.
帶來不愉快，帶來滅亡
The mental power gives you a horrible thing called ego,
思維的力量給你一種可怕被稱為自我的東西
which destroys others.
它摧毀別人
And the emotional power gives you
情緒力量只會
nothing but crying, weeping, and always feeling unhappy,
令你叫喊，哭泣和令你常常感到不快樂。
“Oh, I have done so much of emotional investment
啊！我把我的很多的感情
on such and such person and what did I get?”
投資在這樣的人身上，我得到甚麽？」
So it is not absolute, it’s relative.
所以，這不是絕對的，而是相對的。
And mentally you are zero if you cannot destroy others.
思維上你是零的若你不能摧毀別人
Emotionally you are zero
感情上你也是零的
because you cannot overpower people with your emotions.
若你不能以你的感情去控制別人
So what is your power? Where does your power lie?
那麽，你擁有甚麽力量？
It lies in the Spirit. But even before the Spirit is achieved,
你的力量位於何處？它位於靈。在達至靈之前，
what is your power? Is Kundalini? She’s sleeping.
甚麽是你的力量？是靈量嗎？她在沉睡
Then what is your power?
那麽，甚麽是你的力量？
Is your chastity.
是你的貞操
If a man is chaste, chaste temperament he has
若一位男士有貞操，他擁有貞潔的氣質
and he stands up in his chastity, it acts, it works.
他以他的貞潔站立，它作出行動，那是可以成就事情
But first of all chastity pays dividend in your good health.
首先，貞操在你的健康上支付紅利
From the face of a person you can say
從他的面容上，你可以說
that this person is a chaste man.
他是一位有貞操的人
Like in our Shastras used to say a Saint or a brahmachari,
就像在Shastras，通常一位聖人或一位brahmachari
the one who has never had sex in life,
即從未有性的人
always shining on his face.
面容常常都閃亮
And as we say that the greatest brahmachari was Shri Krishna
我們可以說最偉大的brahmachari是錫呂‧克里希納
who has so many wives.
他有那麽多妻子
Because no wastage of energy, no wastage of attention is on that.
因為祂沒有浪費精力，沒有浪費注意力在這些上
So the whole energy is inside.
祂全部的精力是內在的
I will say today as I was coming by car it was raining,
今天當我坐車子來的時候，正下著雨
it was windy, it was very cold, but we were in the car,
非常大風，也很冷，但因為我們在車內
nothing affected us, because we were quite warm inside the car,
對我們沒有任何影響，我們在車內很暖和
ourselves. We passed through everything, nothing touched us,
我們通過所有，沒有甚麽觸動我們
nothing bothered us, we came away, everything fine. How?
沒有甚麽煩擾我們，我們離開了，每事每物都很好，怎會這樣？
Because we kept to our own vehicle
因為我們在車內
and the vehicle we have is our chastity.
我們的車輛就是我們的貞潔
We are so particular that others must respect us,
我們是那麽特別，別人必須尊重我們
other must give us homage, otherwise we get into tempers.
必須對我們有敬意，若他們不這樣，我們便會生氣
Did you respect yourself? Do you respect yourself?
你是否尊重自己？你是否尊重自己？
It sounds sometimes to people in the West
有時這就像
that Mother is very trying to preach about Indian culture.
母親想向西方人灌輸印度文化
Many people think that way.
很多人都這樣想
But I say that one has to learn science from the West.
但我必須要說，我們必須向西方學習科學
All right. One has to learn other things from the West,
我們必須向西方學習其他事物
aesthetics, of course.
審美學
Paintings and art, maybe, colour schemes.
當然還有繪畫和藝術，或許還有色彩設計
But culture you better learn from Indians.
但在文化方面，你還是向印度人學習比較好
There’s dearth of culture, no culture at all, I find.
這裏缺乏文化，我發現完全沒有文化
What is this culture where a woman is supposed to expose her body?
這是怎樣的文化，婦女裸露她們的身體？
Is a prostitute’s culture, simple as that. Face it up.
是妓女文化，就是這樣簡單，面對它吧。
Where a woman is not supposed to respect her private parts
一處婦女不尊重自己的私處的地方
is no culture whatsoever in the aesthetics of the Divine.
是沒有文化，就算以上天的美學來說也不是
So much so today that they are making a film showing Mary
今天他們竟然為瑪利亞製作一部描述
to be a prostitute. I mean, this is where you have ended up.
她是妓女的電影，我的意思是你必須到此為止
In India even if you say this they’ll beat you nicely - anyone,
在印度若你這樣說，你會被人好好的毆打，任何人都可以
whether Muslim, Hindu, Christian.
無論他是穆斯林，印度人，基督徒
I mean, shocking to hear that the way they talk about Christ.
我的意思是聽到他們這樣談論基督，我感到很震驚
I mean, to an Indian it gives a shock.
對印度人來說，這是一種震動
How can you talk because once you give up your chastity
你怎可以說這些話，因為當你放棄你的貞操
you can not understand that there can be someone
你便不會明白有人可以是
who is absolutely chaste.
完全擁有貞操的
For a thief everybody is a thief.
對一個賊來說，每一個人都是賊
Because you don’t have that respect for your chastity
因為你沒有對貞操那份尊敬
you can not imagine what Christ could have been.
所以你不能想像基督可以是怎麽樣
You can not imagine, you can not accept.
你不能想像，不能接受
Unbearable things are said about Christ.
他們對基督說了一些不能容忍的事情
I tell you, unbearable, I don’t know.
我告訴你，不能容忍，我也不知道
I’ve faced His crucifixion, which was unbearable as it was.
我曾經面對祂被釘十字架，那是不能容忍的
But this kind of a thing you say about somebody;
若你向其他人說這種事情
to an Indian woman if you pass such a remark,
若你對一位印度女士作出這種評語
to an Indian ordinary woman, she would commit suicide.
一位平凡的印度女士，她會自殺
Is never said that anybody comes and says,
不能向任何人這樣說
“You looking very beautiful.” It’s all right,
「你看來很美麗。」
you can say to your mother, “you’re looking nice,” is all right,
你向你的母親這樣說︰「你看來很好。」是可以的
that’s different. But you don’t say to any woman like that.
這就是分別。但你不能對任何女士這樣說
You have to turn yourself out.
你必須要抽身而出
And this is one of the reasons why
這就是為甚麽
people are very hot-tempered.
人們那樣脾氣差的其中一個原因
The magnet within you is Shri Ganesha.
你內在的磁石是錫呂‧格涅沙
Many people know that I have a great sense of direction.
很多人都知道我的方向感很強
That comes through this magnet which is perfect.
這是藉由這種完美的磁石而來
This magnet is the one which keeps you sticking or adjusted
這種吸力令你保持黏貼著靈，調節方向向著靈
or all the time pointed towards Spirit.
或始終向著靈
If you don’t have the sense of chastity you will dangle this way,
若你沒有貞操的意識，你便會搖擺不定
that way. Suddenly you become a very good Sahaja Yogi,
今天你忽然變成一位非常好的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
tomorrow you become a devil –
明天你卻變成魔鬼
because there’s nothing that keeps you binding
因為沒有甚麽約束你
to the great idea of the Spirit. Let us face it up.
令你保持向著靈這個偉大的念頭。讓我們面對它
Now the time has come for all of us, all the Sahaja Yogis,
現在對我們來說時候到了，所有霎哈嘉瑜伽士
that the greatest thing within us is not sex, but is chastity.
我們內在的最偉大的不是性，而是貞操
And that’s what will mature you.
它令你成熟
It’s very amazing how some people were behaving in Bordi,
在Bordi，很驚訝的有些人有這樣的言行
I came to know about it, I was amazed,
當我知道了，我感到很驚訝
how could they behave like this before the villagers of Bordi,
他們怎能在Bordi的村民
who are innocent, simple people?
一些純真，簡單的人面前作出這樣的言行？
But the best part of it that when you indulge into frivolous
最精彩的部分是當你沉醉在輕挑
and nonsensical behaviour, insulting your chastity,
和荒謬的行為，侮辱你的貞操
you really lag in the action of it.
你真的落後了
Like, if you fritter away your petrol, your car can’t move,
就像沒有電油，你的車便不能動
it’s like that, something happens to you.
就像這樣，某些事情發生在你身上
All the time you go on pinching people
你不停的扭痛別人
and frivolously talking to each other and to,
互相說些輕挑的說話
what is the need to do all these, I just don’t understand.
有甚麽需要這樣做，我就是不懂
And then end up in the divorce case.
最後離婚收場
Once I had gone to a Selfridges,
有一次，我走到Selfridges那處
I must tell you a very interesting story.
我必須告訴你這是一個很有趣的故事
And in such a crowd there were two people, man and woman,
在一群人中有二個人，一男一女
kissing each other all the time,
常常都在接吻
least bothered there are other people
並沒有因為
who are also going on the same escalator.
同一部電梯中有很多其他人在而被打擾
Escalator they were kissing, in the thing they were kissing,
在電梯中他們接吻，在其他場合他們接吻
I mean, torturing all the Indians who were there
我的意思是他們在折磨著所有在場的印度人
or maybe the other people, Chinese, for example, Egyptians.
或其他人，又或是中國人，埃及人
Such an exhibition going on. And I saw them next time.
這種展覽持續著，我下一次遇見他們
They were not kissing.
他們沒有接吻
I said, “What happened?”
我說︰「發生了甚麽事？
“We are divorced.”
「我們離婚了。」
I said, “Why were you kissing that day so much?”
我說︰「那天你們為甚麽吻得那麽多？
So they said, “Because we were going to be divorced,
他們說︰「因為我們將要離婚，
so wanted to have the last bit of it.”
所以想最後吻多一點。」
What a level it is. Imagine what a level. What love,
是甚麽層次，試想像是怎樣的層次，怎樣的愛
what feeling you have for anyone, nothing of the kind.
你對任何人有怎樣的感覺，不會是這種吧
All the time quarrelling with each other,
常常爭吵
ending up in the divorce cases and showing off all this.
最終離婚收場，卻炫耀這些
Any deep personality doesn’t show these things outside.
有深度的人格不會在外展示這些
Of course, I’m told here that here in the public school it is said
當然，有人告訴我，在這裏，這裏的公立學校說
that you should never show your emotions outside.
你永遠不要外在的顯示你的情緒
But otherwise you can show anything else,
但你卻可以顯示其他
ridiculous or shameless. But not your emotions.
真是荒謬或無恥，不能顯示你的情緒
What an absurd place it is.
真是一處荒謬的地方
You have accepted all these values
接受所有這些價值
just like sheep, without thinking about it.
我們像綿羊一樣，完全沒有去思考。
Like I was in France, one girl came and she was crying.
像我在法國，有一女孩到來，她正在哭泣
She said, “I will - horrid, horrid,
她說︰「我會…可怕，可怕
I will never go to these psychologists.”
我永遠也不會再到這些心理學家那處
So I said, “Why?”
我問︰「為甚麽？」
“They were saying dirty things about my father.”
「他們說了些有關我父親下流的事情。」
Imagine.
試想像
And people accepted those ideas of this horrible Freud.
人們接受可怕的佛洛依德的那些主意
Is basically wrong. Whether it is historically they are,
基本上是錯的，無論它們是否已經成為歷史
or whatever it is, you better give it up.
或無論怎樣，你還是放棄它吧
Whatever wrong is wrong, in the Divine.
對上天來說，甚麽是錯的就是錯
Whatever is right is right, in the Divine.
甚麽是對的就是對的
But there’s a real objection now,
現在有真正的反對
that people when they go abroad,
當人們走到國外
husband and wife and this and that, they kiss each other
丈夫或妻子，這位或那位，他們接吻
and tease each other. What is the need?
互相諷刺，為甚麽要這樣？
You kiss the person and come and tell Me against that person,
你吻這個人，跟著走來向我說些批評他的說話
I’ve seen it. If there has to be some self-preservation,
我曾經見過這樣。若有甚麽需要自衛
this has to be your chastity, your privacy.
就必定是你的貞操，你的私穩
That’s why you have no willpower to do anything, no willpower.
這就是為甚麽你沒有自制力做任何事情，沒有自制力
Let some stupid fellow come and tell you something,
當一些愚蠢的人來告訴你一些事情時
you’ll say, “All right. We accept.”
你會說︰「好吧，我接受。」
What is the essence of your personality – is your chastity.
你個性的精粹是甚麽，是你的貞操。
And in Sahaja Yoga you can re-establish everything
在霎哈嘉瑜伽，你可以重建任何
whatever you have lost, you can.
你失去的，你可以
That’s why the depth is lacking.
這就是為甚麽缺乏深度
And this is the reason there is no consistency
這就是不能一致的原因
in the temperament of people, no consistency.
人們的品性，不能一致
Now you’ll get twelve hundred people for My lecture
今天有一千二百人來到我的講座
and next day not even one, all lost.
明天可能一個也沒有，全部都遺失了
Because there’s no base, you know. Like a loose connection.
因為沒有根基，就像鬆開了的聯繫
There’s no connection, connection point is your chastity.
沒有了聯繫，連接點就是你的貞操
So there is no consistency, sthaapayati is not there.
沒有一致，stjhaapayati(即可以建立的性質)不存在
If you tell them, “You have to get up in the morning,
若你告訴他們︰「你必須早上起來
have a bath, do some puja,” it’s too much for them.
先洗澡，再做崇拜。」這是非他們的能力所及
But if you tell, say an Indian ladies or Me, if you say that
但若你告訴一位印度女士或告訴我，若你說︰
“that you wear such and such dress,”
「你穿這樣這樣的衣服。」
I just can’t, I just can’t, no, not possible. Is not possible.
我就是穿不了，不，沒有可能，是沒有可能
I can keep the whole night awake,
我可以整晚保持清醒
but that thing I can not do, just cannot do it.
但這樣的事情我就是做不了，只是做不了
So the priorities are changed because where is your attention.
因為你的注意力，你的先後次序改變了
You have everything within you.
你內在擁有所有
You are the storehouse of chastity, which is your power.
你是貞操的貨倉，那是你的力量
Everything within you, nothing has gone out, it’s all there.
所有在你內裏，甚麽也沒有走出去，所有都在那裏
All that fragrance is within you. Is all preserved,
所有芬芳都在你內裏，全都得到保存
don’t condemn yourself. And you are so fortunate
不要責備自己，你是那麽幸運的
I’m here to tell you all about it.
有我告訴你所有這些
You are so fortunate I am with you.
你是那麽幸運的有我與你一起
Do you understand that point?
你們明白這一點嗎？
You don’t have to go to Himalayas;
你不需要走到喜瑪拉雅山
you don’t have to stand on your heads.
你不需要倒立
You don’t have to do anything like that.
你不需要做這樣的事情
You see, formerly these saints used to sit, you know,
你看，之前這些聖人通常都坐在
you won’t believe, in the cold frozen water or on the Himalayas
你不會相信，坐在冰冷的水裏，或是在喜瑪拉雅山
in the open they used to sit for hours together
在空曠處坐上很多小時，去凍僵他們荒謬的念頭
Now that’s not necessary.
現在不再需要這樣
It’s all made very easy. But change your priorities now.
很容易做到。你要改變你的先後次序
The whole attention once goes to your own Spirit
當注意力完全放在你的靈上
you’ll be surprised the whole chart will change.
你會很驚訝整個排行榜會完全改變
What’s the most important thing? To meditate every day.
甚麽事情是最重要的？是每天靜坐
I have seen people who want to do some course, say, for example,
我曾經見過有些人想報讀一些課程，例如，
I told that “You better do some course.”
我告訴你︰「你還是報讀一些課程比較好。」
Every day they will go for that course and join that class
他們每天參加這個課程，參加這個班
and they will work it out and they’ll pass that course
他們都會有成就，他們這個課程得到合格
and do it up and finish it.
盡力去做，去完成課程
But meditation they cannot do regularly.
但他們卻不恆常靜坐
But now there’s a little gap you should understand,
有一個小間隙你必須明白
that once we get the inkling of that joy which is eternal,
當你感受到一點點那種永恆喜樂的跡象
we start moving towards that more and more,
我們便會開始向前移，
more and more and establishing ourselves
移得越來越前，把自己建立在
in the ocean of that joy.
在這個喜樂的海洋中
A little. You see, when somebody wants you to swim,
一點點。當某人想你游泳
you are frightened, you don’t want to do it,
但你感到害怕，你不想游泳
you are very happy on the gross shore,
你樂於在岸邊
you don’t want to swim. Somebody pushes you,
你不想游泳，有人把你推向前
again you are back, “No, baba, I can not do it.”
你又走回來︰「不，爸爸，我做不了。」
But once you learn to swim you enjoy that swimming.
但當你學懂游泳，你享受游泳
And when you like it then you want to do it every day,
當你喜歡上游泳，你便想每天都去游泳
regularly, religiously.
恆常地，虔誠地
So there’s a little gap, which has to be achieved.
這個小間隙，你必須跨越
Second point is that as I’ve been always saying,
第二點是我常常說的
you are lotuses, but under a mire.
你們都是蓮花，但卻陷於污泥中
And you know what mire is,
你們都知道污泥是怎麽樣的
while India is the ocean, so it’s very easy for the lotuses
若印度是海洋，蓮花很容易的
to come out of the water.
從水中走出來
But to come out of the mire is very difficult.
但從污泥中走出來卻非常困難
Say, somebody falls in the mire.
就如你掉進污泥
If you kick it, you go deeper.
若你踢它，你便越陷越深
If you try to do anything you go deeper.
你有任何的動作，你也會越陷越深
Best thing is to keep watching it and still.
最好還是只觀看著，保持不動
And that’s the best way – is to witness yourself.
最佳的途徑，就是觀看自己
But your attention is not all right, how will you witness?
若你的注意力不妥當，你又怎能靜觀？
Attention is: somebody’s going that side –
注意力是某人走在這裏
that person you’ll see. Another person going that –
你看著這個人，另一個人走到那裏
that person you’ll see, must see every person.
你看著這個人，你看著每一個人
But you don’t see the flowers, you don’t see the trees,
但卻看不到花朵，看不到樹木
you don’t see the Mother Earth, you don’t see anything.
看不到母親大地，甚麽也看不到
What you see is something hopelessly bad, worse than you.
你看到的只是一些於事無補的壞事，比你還要差
Today is the day they say one should not see the moon.
今天是一個他們說不要看月亮的日子
If you see the moon it becomes inauspicious
若你看月亮，它會變得不吉祥
and you get a bad name. They say Shri Krishna saw the moon
你會得到壞名字。他們說錫呂‧克里希納看到月亮
and then He got a bad name; He was ranchordas,
所以祂得了一個壞名字。祂是ranchordas
means He had to run away from the battlefield.
意思是祂從戰場中逃跑出來
But that was His trick, He had to run away.
這是祂的把戲，祂必須逃跑
So you are not supposed to see the moon.
你是不應該去看月亮
The reason is, why it is said,
原因是，為甚麽要這樣說
that today we have to see Shri Ganesh,
因為今天我們要會見錫呂‧格涅沙
who is the Mother Earth,
祂是母親大地
who acts through Mother Earth.
祂藉由母親大地作出行動
Most of the things that we have are from the Mother Earth.
我們擁有的大部分東西都是來自母親大地
So this time you must see the Mother Earth,
所以這一次我們必須要去見母親大地
the Kundalini and Shri Ganesh, today.
靈量和錫呂‧格涅沙，即今天
The Mother Earth has created Shri Ganesha.
母親大地創造了錫呂‧格涅沙
So you don’t see anything outside, you don’t even see the moon.
所以你們不要去看任何外在的東西
Just see the Mother Earth.
你甚至不要去看月亮，只看母親大地
Because the Mother Earth in Her love
因為母親大地藉由她的愛
and compassion has done so much for us,
她的慈悲，為你們做了很多事
your Kundalini has done so much for you.
你的靈量也為你們做了很多事
And Her Son, Who is the innocence within us,
而她的兒子，那是我們內在的純真
is to be worshipped today because He has done the maximum.
是我們今天要敬拜的，因為祂為我們做的事是最多
Despite all the insults we have put on Him, all the ridicule,
盡管我們把所有侮辱，所有揶揄
all the filth, all kinds of nonsense,
所有髒話，各種荒謬加在祂的身上
still He stands up like a little child to amuse us.
祂仍然像小孩子一樣站起來逗我們高興
If Shri Ganesha is within you become like a child,
若你內在有錫呂‧格涅沙，你變得像小孩
childlike innocence, you don’t get angry with somebody
像小孩般的純真，你不會生任何人氣
like a dog barks; there are some Sahaja Yogis I know
像狗吠般，我知道有一些霎哈嘉瑜伽士
who all the time barking, just like dogs or beggars in India.
常常像狗隻或印度的乞丐一樣吠叫
But you become like a child who is very sweet,
但你變得像小孩一般非常甜美
who always tries to amuse you,
常常想逗人高興
always tries to say nice things,
常常說些美好的事情
always tries to make you feel happy. The source of such joy.
常常想令你感到快樂，這是喜樂的泉源
And that’s how you become a source of joy,
這就是你怎樣成為快樂的泉源
source of happiness, source of fulfilment.
喜樂的泉源，滿足感的泉源
All the time bubbling with laughter and happiness,
常常都充滿笑聲和快樂
bubbling with beautiful things. How the children amuse you,
充滿美麗的東西。小孩子是怎樣逗你高興
just see and watch.
你只要靜觀
How they come round with little-little hands,
他們的小手怎樣走在你附近
how they work it out.
他們是怎能做到
How they know what is the right thing.
他們是怎樣知道甚麽是對
A child who is a Realized soul is much more sensible
一位已得自覺的孩子比成年人更加敏銳
than a grown up person, I’ve seen that.
我曾經見過這樣。
Like My youngest granddaughter was about, I think,
就像我最小的外孫女
three years of age and the maid was folding My sari
在她約三歲時，女傭在摺疊我的紗麗
and by mistake she put it on the ground.
但她錯把紗麗放在地上
This child just couldn’t bear it. She just lifted the sari,
這孩子就是不能忍受，她把紗麗拿起
put it to her head and put it on the sofa.
放在她的頭上，再放在沙發上
She said, “What you mean by putting this sari on the ground,
她說︰「你為甚麽把紗麗放在地上
what you do know about my Grandmother?
你知不知道我的外祖母是誰？
She is the Goddess of Goddesses
她是女神中的女神
and you put Her sari on the ground.
你竟然把她的紗麗放在地上
The dogs are going to bite you now,” she said, “Be careful.”
狗隻會咬你。」她再說︰「你要小心。」
And she again went and put the sari, kissed it and kissed it
她再把紗麗拿起，吻它，再吻它
and said, “Mother, forgive her, Grandmother, please,
說︰「母親，請原諒她，祖母
forgive this woman, she doesn’t know what she’s done to You”.
請原諒這個婦人，她不知道對你做了些甚麽？
But that sensitivity comes from the depth of your chastity.
這種感性來自你深層的貞操
You listen to the children and you’ll be amazed
當聆聽孩子的說話，你會驚訝
how they talk and what they say, how they behave,
他們是怎樣的說話，說了些甚麽，有怎樣的言行
how they try to amuse you. I mean,
他們是怎樣逗你歡喜，我的意思
in the West children are very much spoiled, I must say,
我的意思是在西方的孩子是被過分寵愛，我必須要說，
they do not amuse you so much, they trouble you quite a lot.
他們不大逗你歡喜，但卻常常令你感到煩擾
Because again, again the same thing.
同樣的原因
If the father and mother don’t have chastity,
若父親和母親沒有貞操
the children don’t feel all right, they don’t feel peaceful,
孩子便會感到不妥當，他們不會感到平和
they’ll become restless, and then they develop
他們變得不安寧
the same restlessness within themselves.
他們的內在同樣發展了這種不安寧
A chaste man can never get possessed, take it from Me,
一位貞潔的人永遠不會被鬼附，就像我
can never get possessed. You might be very intelligent,
永遠不會被鬼附。你可能非常聰明
you might be anything, you might be a great writer,
你可能是甚麽，你可能是一位偉大的作家
but you can get possessed. But a chaste man,
但你卻會被鬼附。但一位貞潔的人
an ordinary chaste person can never get possessed.
一位普通但有貞潔的人，永遠不會被鬼附
Bhoots are afraid of chaste people.
亡靈害怕貞潔的人
If one chaste person is going on the road, all the bhoots run away.
若一位貞潔的人走在路上，所有的亡靈都會走開
They just run away. At least I’ve known many cases
他們只會跑開。最少我知道很多這樣的例子
but some of them I can tell you,
我可以告訴你一些
that there were three of them,
有三個人
who used to go by motorcycle in the night
常常坐電單車在晚上
about twelve o’clock on a road.
約十二時走在路上
And some people who were possessed wrote letters to Me,
有一些被鬼附的人寫信給我
saying that “Please don’t allow them to go there in the night,
說︰「請不要容許他們在晚上走在路上
because where should we go and stay?”
不然我們可以往那裏去和留在那裏？」
I was amazed. These are the people
我感到很驚訝，這些人都是
who were possessed by some sort of horrible bhoots
被可怕的亡靈所依附的
who used to go and rest on these trees in the night
他們晚上常常都在這些樹上休息
where these three persons used to go on the motorcycle
就是那三個人常常坐電單車經過的樹
and they actually wrote letters to Me.
他們寫信給我
Very possessed people, I knew them, saying that,
那些被鬼附的人，我知道他們，信上說︰
“Ask them not to go that way, because where are we to live?”
「叫他們不要走這條路，不然我們可以住在那裏？」
And they were like mad, mad people themselves.
他們像瘋子一樣，一群瘋癲的人
I said, “Why did you write like this?”
我說︰「為甚麽你要這樣寫？
They said, “These people go that way and they trouble us.”
他們說︰「這些人走在這裏，他們令我們感到煩擾。」
And the negative within us disappears
我們內在的負面能量消失
with the light of Shri Ganesha.
因著錫呂‧格涅沙的光
You can see it so clearly in another person.
你可以在另人一個人身上清楚看到
If you don’t have chastity you can never see
若你沒有貞操，你永遠也看不到
who is unchaste or chaste, you can not.
誰人有貞潔而誰人沒有，你不能
Everybody just the same, “Very good, very good,
每一個人都是「非常好，非常好
very nice person, very nice person”.
非常好的人，非常好的人
I mean real possessed people are certified as very good people,
我的意思是真正被鬼附的人會被証明是非常好的人
in Sahaja Yoga also sometimes and I start wondering,
在霎哈嘉瑜伽有時也一樣，我開始覺得奇怪
“What’s happening, what is it? How is it these people
「甚麽事發生了？這是甚麽？
are certified as that? Can’t they feel it?” There’s no light.
為甚麽這些人被証明是這樣？他們感覺不到它嗎？」沒有光，
Even if you get your Realization,
就算你已經得到自覺
even if your Spirit is working out your collective consciousness,
就算你的靈已經把你帶到集體意識
even if you are giving Self Realization to others,
就算你給予別人自覺
you are nowhere if you have no chastity.
若你沒有貞操，你甚麽也成就不了
That’s like a broken glass which is trying to reflect something;
就像一片破的玻璃想反映某些物品
it can never give the right picture.
它永遠也不能反映該物品的正確影像
It’s so important. And I have to tell you this now.
這是非常重要的，我必須現在告訴你
The time has come for Me to tell you – this is the snag in our life.
現在是告訴你們的時候，這是我們生命中的障礙
First thing people will ask, “Whom I’m going to marry?”
首先人們會問︰「我將與誰人結婚？」
What is such a hurry? Of course, marriage I call it
為甚麽這樣匆忙？當然，我稱婚姻
an auspicious thing, marriage should be there,
為吉祥的事，婚姻必須存在
there should be a collective sanction, everything, but for what?
必須有集體的認同，所有，但為甚麽要這樣？
To adore the chastity within us. Then they are married,
就是去敬拜我們內在的貞操。因此，他們結婚
then they have children. Then they want to have a house,
有孩子，跟著他們想有自己的房子
then they want to have this.
他們想擁有這些
There’s whole such an insular business goes on, and on, and on,
這樣超然的事情在繼續，繼續不停
and the light of your life doesn’t spread.
你生命中的光得不到傳播
But I’ve known people who were just in the hell
我知道有些在地獄的人
and have come out and have spread light,
他們走出來，傳播光
beautiful meteoric heights they have achieved.
他們到達短暫而輝煌美麗的高度，
I’ve seen people like that.
我曾經見過這樣的人
So today you have come to worship Shri Ganesha - within yourself.
今天你們是敬拜你內在的錫呂‧格涅沙
What is Me to worship as Ganesha I don’t understand.
我就是不明白為甚麽敬拜我為格涅沙
Because I’m That. When you are worshiping Me
因為我就是這樣。當你敬拜我
you want to have that Shri Ganesh within you awakened.
你希望你內在的格涅沙得到喚醒
Let that be awakened within you.
就讓祂在你內在被喚醒
Let what I say becomes the mantra to awaken that within you,
就讓我所說的話變成喚醒你內在的祂的口訣
so that as My children you enjoy the bliss of chastity
因此，作為我的孩子，你享受貞操的祝福
as I have enjoyed all My human life and all My Divine lives.
就如我享受我的人類生活以及我的神聖生活
You enjoy the same quantity, that’s what I want.
你同樣享受這質量，這是我所希望的
At least you should have the taste of it.
對此你最少能有所體驗
I’m telling you about something
我要告訴你一些
which you may not have heard before.
你可能不曾聽過的事情
But you never heard about Kundalini also.
你從來沒有聽過靈量
You had never heard about Self Realization like this.
從來也沒有聽過自覺
But today I think by chance, absolutely in a Sahaja way,
今天很偶然地，完全以霎哈嘉的方式
this Puja was arranged. I was to have this Puja in Bombay.
這個崇拜被安排在這裏，我本想這個崇拜在孟買舉行
It was all organized; people were all willing to come there
已經安排好了，但人們卻樂意來到這裏
to do this puja. I mean, a Ganesha Puja in England
作這個崇拜，我的意思是一個在英國
or in the West is so important that I thought better have it one,
或在西方國家舉行的，是非常重要的，所以我想還是
without the right time in Rome,
有一個在這裏舉行，羅馬沒有合適的時間
which is one of the basic things
那是其中一個基本的原因
which has ruined the chastity of human beings.
破壞人類的貞操
Romans started it and others carried on.
首先是羅馬人開始，其他人跟隨
But it was to be here in Brighton at the Lotus Feet of Sadashiva.
但必須在布賴頓，在至高顯婆神的蓮足作這個崇拜
But the English must know
但英國人必須知道
that they have got such a golden land
你們擁有這黃金土地
and they don’t deserve it. They have to deserve it.
他們不值得擁有它，他們必須令自己值得擁有它
Imagine, you are living in the land of Sadashiva
試想像，你們是住在至高顯婆神的土地上
where even water beads also the snow –
那裏甚至水珠，還有雪
means like distilled water, clean, clear, white.
也像蒸餾水般清潔，清澈，潔白
Where Shri Ganesha is the One
在這裏，錫呂‧格涅沙為
Who washes the feet of His Father.
為祂父親洗腳
Where the chastity itself resides as your Mother.
而貞操則以你的母親的形相住在這裏
And you have to deserve that coveted position.
你必須值得處於這個令人垂涎的位置
English Sahaja Yogis have to come up very much.
英國的霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須盡力追上來
Just the opposite English were.
是跟英國人的相反方向
Coming from Sadashiva’s land just the opposite.
來自至高顯婆神土地的卻是相反
Tremendous arrogance, arrogance so horrible,
他們有極大的傲慢，傲慢是很可怕
which one can not think in Shiva’s place.
在顯婆神的地方是不能想像有這傲慢
All unchaste people are arrogant.
所有沒有貞潔的人都是傲慢的
Otherwise, how can they forgive themselves?
否則，他們怎能寛恕自己？
You talk to any prostitute, in two minutes you’ll find out
你與任何妓女交談，兩分鐘內
she’s a prostitute because she’s extremely arrogant,
你會發現她是一位妓女，因為她極之傲慢
“What’s wrong? I’m a prostitute, so what?”
有甚麽不妥？我是妓女，那又怎樣？
Arrogance is a sign of unchaste personality.
傲慢是不貞潔品格的徵兆
And such a person also becomes insular
這個人變得超然物外
because he’s ashamed, ashamed to face others.
因為他感到羞愧，愧於面對其他人
But a chaste personality is open,
但一位擁有貞操品格的人是坦率的
why should he be afraid of anyone?
他為甚麽要害怕任何人？
Talks to everyone nicely,
他與每一個人友善地交談
kind to everyone in all innocence and simplicity
以純真和直率的態度對待人
without falling in love in every third person you come across.
不會愛上任何他接觸到的第三者
And that, one has to realize that this country is given to you
因此，你們必須知道，給你這個國家
with a purpose and if you do not come up to that level,
是有目的的，若你不能到達這水平
you’ll be thrown away.
你將會被丟棄
So respecting your chastity is real respecting Me,
尊重你的貞操才是真正的尊重我
because I reside within you as chastity.
因為我以貞操住在你的內裏
If Shri Ganesha is the auspiciousness,
若錫呂‧格涅沙就是吉祥
I reside within you as chastity.
我就是你內在的貞操
Chastity is never aggressive,
貞操永遠不富侵略性
is never harsh, because there’s no need, you know.
永遠不會苛刻，因為沒有這個需要
No need, you are so powerful, you are so powerful,
你知道沒有這個需要，你是那麽有力量
that there is no need to aggress anyone.
沒有需要侵略任何人
Why should you aggress, you are not frightened of anyone.
為甚麽你要富侵略性，你並不懼怕任何人
It’s so generous, it’s so kind, it’s so beautiful,
是那麽慷慨，那麽仁慈，那麽漂亮
always fresh and young, yet so sublime and so dignified.
常常保持清新和年青，而又那麽崇高和有尊嚴
Now twelve years have passed since I’ve been here.
我首次到達這裏已經過了十二年
Two more years, very intense work is needed,
再多二年，需要非常熱切地工作
within and without. Within we have to work very hard
在內和在外。在內，我們必須非常勤奮地工作
for these two years, very hard,
這二年，非常勤奮
real tapasya we have to go into,
我們必須行真正的苦行
all of us, whether men or women.
全部人，不分男女
And then we’ll see.
那麽我們便會見到
I can say that, we have done good job,
我可以這樣說，我們已經做得非常好
with little jump, courage and faith we can achieve a lot.
藉由小小的跳躍，勇氣和信心，我們可以成就很多
Have faith in yourself.
對自己要有信任
Not mental faith but actual chastity is faith.
不是思維上的信任而是來自真正貞潔的信任
Chastity is the consolidation of your faith.
貞潔鞏固你的信心
When you have faith in God, you are chaste.
當你對神有信心，你便有貞操
When you have faith in yourself you are chaste.
當你對自己有信心，你便有貞操
You have faith in your wife, you are chaste.
當你對妻子有信心，你便有貞操
Why should you have faith in your wife?
為甚麽你對妻子有信心？
Because you are a chaste person, how can she be unchaste?
因為你是一位擁有貞操的人，她又怎能沒有貞操？
Your faith in your child - is chastity, because you are chaste,
你對你的孩子有信心，是貞操，因為你是貞操
how can your child be anything else?
你的孩子又怎會是其他任何東西？
Crystalline form of faith is chastity.
貞操是信心的結晶
And that you can have even before Realization. Many have.
你甚至在未得自覺前已可擁有它，很多人也是這樣
Actually like the camphor, which, you see,
像樟腦，
is volatile and evaporates into the fragrance,
具揮發性，消失在香氣中
in the same way we can say chastity acts into faith.
同樣，你也可以說，貞操運作成信心
If you don’t have chastity you cannot have faith,
若你沒有貞操，你對任何事
in anything.
也沒有信心
Because either you are dealing with your emotions
因為你一是情感上
that you are emotionally attached to Me
依附於我
or maybe you are mentally attached to Me.
又或是思維上依附於我
But if you have sense of chastity faith will be apparent.
但若你有貞操的意識，信心便很明顯
Within yourself you don’t have to have faith,
在你內裏，你不需要有信心
“Now Mother I will have faith within myself.” You cannot.
「母親，我將會有信心。」你不能
Faith is something, which is volatile
信心的性質是，富揮發性的
and the volatile fragrance comes from chastity.
而富揮發性的芬芳，是從貞操而來
So from today we are not going to look at the stars or the moon,
所以從今天開始，我們不看星星或月亮
but you are going to look at the Mother Earth.
只看母親大地
In the Universe She represents the Kundalini,
在宇宙中，她代表靈量
is nothing but chastity. She’s just chastity.
她甚麽也不是只是貞操，她只是貞操
Can you believe it? What a power.
你相信嗎？有怎樣的力量
Motherhood, everything is chastity.
母性，每事每物都是貞操
Fatherhood, any relationship is chastity.
父性，任何關係都是貞操
Purity is again the fragrance of chastity.
純真也是貞操的芬芳
Goodness, compassion, everything comes from chastity,
善良的，慈悲的，每事每物都來自貞操
a sense of chastity, which is not mental.
貞操的意識，那不是思維而來的
If you are mentally chaste, you can be horrid.
若你只是思維上有貞操，你可以很可怕
Like some of the nuns are or some of those people
像一些尼姑或類似的人
who are austere, not that.
一些禁慾的人，不是這樣
Chastity is an innate built-in Kundalini within you,
貞操是天生的，是內置靈量在我們內裏
which acts because it understands Me.
它能運作是因為它明白我
She understands Me. She knows Me,
她明白我，她知道我
She’s part and parcel of Me, It’s My reflection.
她是我的一部分，她是我的反映
So make your Kundalini strong by being chaste.
所以她藉由貞操來令你的靈量強壯
People try to do things to look very attractive and this and that.
人們嘗試做一些事情令自己看來很吸引
Don’t waste your energy like this;
不要這樣浪費你的精力
you are saints, live like saints.
你是聖人，要活得像聖人
Traditionally as we live, we have to live that way
從傳統而來的生活，我們必須像這樣的生活
and evolve out of the tradition; don’t do something new,
從傳統中進化，不要做些新的
something absurd, nonsensical.
可笑的和荒謬的事情
We don’t have to attract anyone.
我們不需要吸引任何人
Chastity is the fragrance in the flower,
貞操就像花朵裏的香氣
which attracts the bees,
吸引蜜蜂的
is the honey of the flower,
是花朵裏的花蜜
is the essence of our existence.
也是我們存在的精粹
So this time you are all coming to India,
所以這一次，你們全都來到印度
I have to request you to respect Me by not misbehaving.
我請求你們尊重我，不要言行不當
Not childishly behaving in the manner you see in the pictures
不要作出幼稚和荒謬的言行
and the films and all that nonsense.
像在電影中看到的
You are above all that.
你們全都高於這些
Attention, achievements are to be seen
你的注意力和成就可從
from the seat of your chastity.
你貞操的位置看到
We can’t leave our seats,
我們不能離開我們的座位
whether we are acclaimed or not makes no difference.
無論我們有否被讚賞是毫無分別的
Like all these avadhootas they’ll say,
就像這些avadhootas，他們說︰
takiya sodaa sana - means we’ll not leave our seats.
「takiya soda sana」，意思是我們不會離開我們的座位
We are in our seats. This is our seat, in the lotus.
我們在我們的座位裏，這是我們的座位，在蓮花裏
We can’t leave the lotus. We are sitting in the lotus.
我們不能離開蓮花，我們是坐在蓮花裏
That’s our seat. Then all these nonsensical things
這是我們的座位。跟著你會放棄所有
that you have acquired will drop out.
荒謬的事物
You’ll see you’ll become beautiful being.
你會看到自己變成漂亮的存有
All bhoots will run away, all catches will run away.
所有亡靈會跑掉，所有阻塞會跑掉
But is not austerity, again and again I’m telling you.
不是過著禁慾的生活，我要再次告訴你
It is respect of your Being. As you respect Me outside,
這是對你的存有的尊重。當你外在的尊重我
you respect Me within. As simple as that.
你也要內在的尊重我，就是這樣簡單
Today is a great day for us to be worshipping Shri Ganesh.
今天是一個偉大的日子，我們敬拜錫呂‧格涅沙
He is the first and the foremost to be worshipped.
祂是首先亦是最先被敬拜的
And when you worship Him, you must realize
當你敬拜祂，你必須知道
that you are worshipping His manifestation as well,
你也是敬拜祂所顯示的
that is of Christ. Anybody who talks cheaply about Christ,
就是基督。任何人對基督說些低下的說話
you should abhor such a person.
你必須厭惡這些人
You cannot intellectualize Christ. Anybody who does it,
你不能把基督理性化，任何這樣做的人，
just have nothing to do with that person.
也與你毫不相干
Christ is innocence.
基督是純真
If you don’t have the depth of your chastity
若你沒有深層的貞操
you can’t understand Him. You cannot worship Him.
你是不能理解祂，不能敬拜祂
That’s the best they could do, is to finish your chastity
他們可以做的也只是令你的貞操完蛋
so that you never recognize Him.
因此你永遠也不能把基督認出
All that comes to you through your meditative efforts.
所有這些成果都是藉由靜坐而來
Now the effort is to be just that you have to be meditative.
你必須靜坐才得到成果
That’s all. Keep your meditation on.
就是這樣。要恆常靜坐
Try to be meditative. See things.
嘗試保持靜坐的狀態，看事物
What is witness state is nothing but that you are meditative.
靜觀狀態就是你處於靜坐的狀態
So I have decided also that I’ll meet the Brighton people
我決定與布賴頓的人見面
here tomorrow morning and I will meet all the English people
在明天早上，我會與全英國的人見面
if possible day after tomorrow evening
有可能的，在後天見面
to tell them how important it is for them to achieve
告訴他們達致純真的狀態
that state of purity. I think it’s working out.
是何等重要，我想已經開始有成效了
I really work very hard,
我真的很幸勤地工作
you have no idea how much I work hard.
你不會知道我工作得多勤奮
But this is also they said that, is an idea that people think
這也是他們說的，人們視別人
that others should do all their work.
必須做所有的工作
This is like pound saving, this saving, that saving
就像挽救英鎊，挽救這些，挽救那些
and also labour saving. Let Mother do all the job for us.
也挽救勞工，讓母親為我們做所有的工作
Mother is looking after us. She should get up in the morning.
母親照顧我們，她必須早上起床
She should do meditation.
她必須靜坐
There is no saving.
拯救不是這樣的
You can save everything else if you just know
你可以拯救任何事物，只要你知道
how to save your Spirit. Only your ascent is important.
怎樣拯救你的靈，只有你的昇進是最重要的
Once you ascend, everything is saved.
當你昇進了，每事每物便會得到拯救
But first save yourself.
但首先要拯救自己
For that you have to put in effort. You have to work hard.
為此你必須盡力，必須幸勤地工作
You have to go deep into you, evolve yourself.
必須深入自己，進化自己
You are quite capable of it. Do not blame anyone;
你有足夠能力這樣做，不要責怪任何人
do not blame your wife, mother, father, country anything.
不要責怪你的妻子，你的母親，你的父親，你的國家，或任何事物。
Everyone can work it out.
每一個人都可以成就到
Don’t see other people, see yourself,
不要看著其他人，只看著自己︰
“How far I have gone? What have I contributed?
我走了多遠？我有甚麽貢獻？
Let me go ahead with it.” Every one of you.
讓我走在前面吧。」你們每一個人
I am thankful that all the people
我很感謝你們所有人
have come from all over England.
你們都是來自英國各地
It was right thing to do it in a way,
這是正確的事情應該這樣做
but this country must be created of that level
這個國家必須被創造成這個層次
that it becomes pilgrimage for everybody to come here.
變成每個人到來朝聖的地方
On the contrary it should not happen
相反地，不應是
that once they come to England,
當他們來到英國之後
after that they never come to Sahaja Yoga.
他們永遠也不再來霎哈嘉瑜伽
Could happen, could happen with the arrogance
這是可能發生的，這是可能的若人們都是傲慢
that people have may be that it might become like that,
若人們都是傲慢的，這是可以發生
that once they come here they’ll say,
當他們來到這裏，他們會說
“No more Sahaja Yoga, had enough of it.”
「不再要霎哈嘉瑜伽，已經夠了。」
The other way round in India, once they go to India they stick on it.
在印度卻相反，當他們來到印度，他們黏貼著印度
I have known some people that they came to England
我知道當有些人來到英國
and the way they, some of the Sahaja Yogis behaved
他們看到一些霎哈嘉瑜伽士的言行
and some of the ashrams run, they just ran away.
一些集體靜室是怎樣被管理，他們因此跑掉。
“Mother nothing doing,
「母親沒有做些甚麽
we are not going to be in Sahaja Yoga anymore
當看到一些已發展的英國霎哈嘉瑜伽士的言行
after seeing your developed Sahaja Yogis in England
一處你已工作了十二年的國家
where you have worked for twelve years.”
我們不再來霎哈嘉瑜伽了
So today we are sitting on this beautiful land of England
今天我們坐在這漂亮的英國土地上
and we have certain debts to be paid,
在這個國家出生
to be born in this country,
我們需要還債
and the debt is that we have to be great Sahaja Yogis.
要還的債是我們必須成為偉大的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
You can make out, very easily, who is a great Sahaja Yogi.
你可以看到，非常容易，誰是偉大的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
When you say that, “shut that window,”
當你說︰「把窗關掉吧。
you’ll find most of them will be sitting looking at others.
你會看到大部分人都是坐著看著其他人
I don’t say they are all English but could be.
我不是說他們全是英國人，但可能是
Make others work is not the way.
不是要其他人做
You have to be really very dedicated.
你必須是非常委身
You are not of that level, believe Me you are not of that level.
你仍未到達這程度，相信我，你仍未到這達程度
Don’t look at other people who are here.
不要只看著坐在這裏的其他人
You are very different type of people. You are special people.
你是非常不同種類的人，你是特別的人
Try to be alert, respect yourself because you are English
嘗試有警覺性，尊重自己，因為你是英國人
and that you have a special responsibility.
你肩負一個特別的任務
So may God bless you.
願神祝福你
All the way he has brought the water of River Godhavari
他把流經納西克(Nasik)的河流的
which flows in the Nasik, in the river, Nasik.
河水帶來
You see you know that where Shri Rama and Shri Sita
你們都知道錫呂‧羅摩，錫呂‧悉旦以及
and Lakshmana all lived there in Nasik.
拉斯曼都是住在納西克
And this river is called as the Ganges of the south. Godhavari.
這河流被稱為南方的恆河，Godhavari
He got the water from Godhavari. See the vibrations flowing.
他從Godhavari取水，看看生命能量在流通
In the country where the rivers even are mantras,
在一處甚至河流是口訣
their names are mantras - the whole credit goes to the Saints,
他們的名字也是口訣的國家，榮譽歸於聖人
to the people who lived so religiously and so much full of purity
歸於人民，他們活得很虔誠，充滿著純真
that the rivers, even if you take their names the vibration comes.
就算是河流，若你說出它們的名字，生命能量也會到來
See? Why not one day Thames becomes like that?
你看？為甚麽泰晤士河有天不可以變成這樣？
Through your punyas it should be.
藉由你的功德，這是可以的
Every particle of this earth should become vibrated
這個地球的每一個微粒必須得到生命能量
through your punyas only.
只能藉由你的功德
Now we have to see that Shri Ganesha state.
現在，讓我們看看錫呂‧格涅沙的狀態，，
The people who have to worship, we have to see
我們所敬拜的，讓我們看看
who are the people who have to worship.
誰人可以敬拜
Very difficult situation.
這是非常困難的處境
Get the small children, that’s the best.
讓小孩子吧，他們是最好的
Come along. Nira. Come along.
來吧，Nira，來吧
Yes, yes you both come along.
是，你們兩位來吧
Very good. Great. Below ten years. All right. Sit down.
非常好，十歲以下，好吧，坐下
All of them should be below ten years.
他們全都必須十歲以下
Not below two but below ten.
不是兩歲以下而是十歲以下
All right. Come, come, come, all of you.
好吧，來吧，來吧，你們全部人
Very good children, must say.
非常好的孩子，我必須要說
Tremendous they are. Aren’t they?
他們很棒，是嗎？
What we are going to do is to wash Mataji´s Feet.
我們要做的是為母親清洗蓮足
Alright? How do we wash, she is putting water on my Feet
好嗎？該怎樣洗，她把水澆在我的雙腳
and you just have to rub. Alright.
你只要去按摩
Come along, four at the time.
來吧，每一次四位
Now who are the four?
現在那四位？
She will put the water,
她會放些水
you rub, now you rub It,
而你則按摩，現在你去按摩
you rub My Foot.
去按摩我的腳